Guide to the Darrin Zammit Lupi photojournalism archive, 2004-2017 RL.11613
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Malta Detention, 2004-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints; 12.57 Gigabytes 1821 files (147 tiff, 1646 jpeg, 20 png, 8 pdf)
  - TIFF images (electronic files), 2004-2013; 147 files (.tif); 12 GB
    - Sleeping migrants, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3002 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0222)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants sleep on their beds in a dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Keep your law in my heart..., 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3181 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0223)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant holds a religious picture at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Names, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3206 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0224)
      Names are seen written on a partition wall at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Looking outside (2), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3025 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0225)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant looks out of a barred window at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Improvised footwear, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3242 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0226)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants wear improvised footwear at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Hanging out to dry (1), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3255 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0227)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant hangs washed clothes on a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Hanging out to dry (2), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3045 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0228)
      Wet clothes and a towel hang out dry on razor wire at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Hiding his face, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3280 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0229)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant covers his face as he sits next to a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - In the corner, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3098A (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0230)
      A 29-year-old Eritrean migrant stands against a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Standing beneath barbed wire, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3296 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0231)
      Migrants mill around in a courtyard at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Newly-arrived 18-year-old man from Senegal, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3326 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0232)
      A newly-arrived 18-year-old migrant from Senegal looks through a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Waiting to see the doctor (3), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3336 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0233)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant waits for a medical examination at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Holy pictures (3), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3338 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0234)
      Holy pictures are seen near a key locker in the guardroom at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Sitting against the fence, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3116 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0235)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants sit against a fence at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Crushing bread, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3127 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0236)
      An Eritrean migrant crushes bread to make a paste in her dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Woman next to bunk beds (1), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3371 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0237)
      A migrant stands next to bunk bed in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Woman next to bunk beds (2), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3136 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0238)
    - Bread, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3143 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0239)
      A migrant looks at pieces of bread in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Woman next to bunk beds (3), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3434 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0240)
    - Poster protest, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3469 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0241)
      An Eritrean migrant hides his face behind a poster calling for his freedom in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Reading the Koran (1), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3164 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0242)
      A Somali migrant prays with the Koran at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Back/Left, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3512 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0243)
      A sub-Saharan African migrant sits on his bed in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Reading the Koran (2), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3518 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0244)
      A Somali migrant sits next to a barred window as he prays with the Koran at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Woman in garbasaar (shawl), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3561 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0245)
      A Somali migrant sits in a courtyard at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Women in courtyard, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3578 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0246)
      Somali migrants sit in a courtyard at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Looking from behind curtains, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3592 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0247)
      A Somali migrant looks through curtains over her bed in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Religious graffiti, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3593 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0248)
      Graffiti with religious wording is seen on a wall in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Wall drawings, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3188A (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0249)
      Graffiti is seen on a wall in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Graffiti-covered wall, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3191 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0250)
      A Somali migrant makes paper bracelets beneath a graffiti-covered wall in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Lying on her bed, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3606 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0251)
      A Somali migrant lies on her bed in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Somali woman making paper bracelets, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3617 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0252)
    - Crossed wrists, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3620 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0253)
      A Somali migrant crosses her wrists as form of protest against her detention at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Soldier walks into migrants' dormitory, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3625 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0254)
      A Somali migrant sits on her bed as a Maltese soldier walks into her dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Peeling an orange, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3644 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0255)
      Migrants walk along a corridor at Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Organising meals, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3649 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0256)
      An Armed Forces of Malta Detention Services soldier organises meals for immigrants at Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Woman in green, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3659 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0257)
      A Somali migrant walks in a courtyard at Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
  - Large photographic prints, 2006-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints
    Related Materials
    Digital images of these prints are available in this collection guide, in the tiffs series. There are also low-resolution images and contact sheets with related images available; these are only accessible onsite, in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    - In the corner, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: MG_3098A (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0021)
      A 29-year-old Eritrean migrant stands against a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - Boredom, 2012 July 17; Legacy id: MG_4411 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0022)
      African illegal immigrants mill around at the Safi detention centre in Safi, outside Valletta, July 17, 2012. Illegal immigrants arriving on the island of Malta are detained for up to 18 months, a policy which the United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR) has said urgently needs a comprehensive review following the death of a Malian immigrant while in custody last month, according to local media. There are currently around 1000 immigrants being held in detention, according to government officials.
    - On the window ledge, 2012 July 17; Legacy id: JM_97231 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0023)
    - West African immigrant outside his room, 2009 March 14; Legacy id: MG_3391 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0024)
      A West African illegal immigrant stands outside his room during a fact-finding visit by European Justice Commissioner Jacques Barrot (not pictured) at the Lyster Detention Centre in Hal Far, outside Valletta, March 14, 2009.
    - Baby behind bars, 2011 April 19; Legacy id: MG_3170 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0025)
      An Ethiopian immigrant carries her two-week old child at the Lyster Detention Centre in Hal Far, outside Valletta April 19, 2011. Around 1,100 African immigrants fleeing the violence in Libya have arrived in Malta over the past month, according to officials.
    - Woman in gasbasar (shawl), 2013 July 19; Legacy id: ZL_3561 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0026)
      A Somali migrant sits in a courtyard at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - Newly arrived 18-year old man from Senegal, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: ZL_3326 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0027)
      A newly-arrived 18-year-old migrant from Senegal looks through a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - Wondering what it's like out there, 2008 July 15; Legacy id: C4W1417 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0028)
      An African would-be immigrant holds onto a perimeter fence in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa.
    - Despairing immigrant at Lyster barracks Safi detention centre, 2006 March 23; Legacy id: C4W2891 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0029)
      An illegal immigrant cries as he hangs onto a perimeter fence at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Lyster barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration.
    - Somali woman making paper bracelets, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: ZL_3617 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0030)
      A Somali migrant makes paper bracelets beneath a graffiti-covered wall in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - Lying on her bed, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: ZL_3606 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0031)
      A Somali migrant lies on her bed in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - No more football, 2013 July 19; Legacy id: ZL_5082 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0032)
      An old soccer ball is caught in a razor wire fence at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources.
    - Poster protest, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: ZL_3469 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0033)
      An Eritrean migrant hides his face behind a poster calling for his freedom in a dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds 236 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
    - Waiting…, 2013 July 19; Legacy id: ZL_5063 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0034)
      Would-be immigrants stand near an Armed Forces of Malta guard (2nd R) at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta, July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources.
    - Migrants at Safi detention centre, 2013 July 19; Legacy id: ZL_4990 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0035)
      Would-be immigrants sit in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources.
    - Dhuhr (noon) prayers at Safi detention centre (5), 2012 July 17; Legacy id: MG_4554 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0036)
      Muslim illegal immigrants take part in midday prayers at the Safi detention centre in Safi, outside Valletta, July 17, 2012. Illegal immigrants arriving on the island of Malta are detained for up to 18 months, a policy which the United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR) has said urgently needs a comprehensive review following the death of a Malian immigrant while in custody last month, according to local media. There are currently around 1000 immigrants being held in detention, according to government officials.
    - Incarceration, 2006 March 23; Legacy id: BE9A1900 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0037)
      An illegal immigrant holds onto a perimeter fence at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration.
    - Watching from behind the fence at Safi detention centre, 2013 July 19; Legacy id: MG_1648 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0038)
      Would-be immigrants walk in a courtyard at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced.
    - Hands and feet out, 2012 July 17; Legacy id: JM97371 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0039)